hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
in this session we are going to discuss
how we can execute our manual tests in
Tosca Commander what we can also do is
we can execute our automated execution
list as a manual test case
now consider this particular scenario so
in this scenario when we executed this
it failed from a certain step
but we don't have time currently to fix
the remaining steps in this automated
test case
and we need to provide the results to
the testing team so that it can make a
decision on whether they want to go
ahead with the release or not
in such type of scenario where you don't
have time and you still want to provide
the results to the management then then
what you can do is you can quickly
execute this as a manual test case and
just verify whether the application is
working correctly or not
so how you can do that now we can
execute a manual test okay from an
execution list by right clicking and
then there will be an option to run as
manual test case you can also use the
shortcut Ctrl shift and M
now this will be also available for the
folder level the execution list level or
at a execution entry level okay so you
can do it from anywhere
now when you click on this it displays a
checklist window
okay and there you can see all the
different steps all the different values
which have been used all the action
modes and all the previous results
so let's see what are the options
available here okay we can set any
particular test step to pass or field
right from here as you can see there is
a pass option and there is a fail option
so as you go through each of the step
along with the application you are
verifying it manually and you are
setting the results of each test step
also what you can do you can insert a
particular comment you can insert a
attachment or you can even take a
screenshot and attach it to the
particular test step okay so let's
continue with the first step so the
first step it tells you to go to this
particular uh
demo
webshop.resentis.com right so let's go
to this particular website and you can
see the website is opening so I'm going
to uh click on this pass option and this
will pass the result
now you can always go ahead and clear
the result whenever you want okay so
once you have set the result you can
always clear the result back and you
will see that uh the result of this
particular folder has been set to one
and the overall there are 64 test steps
out of this one has passed okay
and then you have to click on register
okay so let's go back here
and I'm going to click on register
so it is showing me the register page
and then I'm going to pass this
particular test step
okay now what I want to do is I want to
take a screenshot so let's take a
screenshot here so that we can attach it
okay into our particular results
so you can see you can annotate with
arrow line
um there are lots of different options
there is text box as well or you can
just save and close okay
so this way you can go through each and
every step and then you can mark it pass
or field and this way you can execute
any particular test case now this could
also be converted into a live document
because you can attach screenshots you
can annotate them you can add
attachments or even you can enter a
comment
okay so here I can say
this step has passed now let's look at
some of the other options which are
available with this particular checklist
you can always go ahead and collapse
this checklist when you are trying to
verify your test case manually okay so
what it will do it will make it a
collapsed window so that you can look at
your application and you can perform the
steps here
okay to expand it back you can click on
this expand option also there is a mini
size uh of this particular window so if
I click on this you will see it will
only display the current the step which
you are currently executing and then uh
the other details could be hidden so
that you have got a minimized window
okay
now going back you can click on full
size and this window will be again
displayed back right
now looking at some of the other options
which are available on the top menu bar
you can see uh if we have finished our
manual test steps execution and we think
that we can continue uh with the
remaining steps as an automated test
execution then what we can do we can set
all the remaining test steps to enable
automated okay so when you click on this
option enable automation all the
remaining test steps will become
automated and from here on you can run
it as an automated test case okay or you
can change it back again to manual test
case
you can also inject data value into your
system under test so by clicking on this
inject data value it will send the value
of the currently selected test step or
tester value to the system under test
also the same set passed and set field
options are available on the top menu so
either you can do it at the desktop
level from the result column or you can
also do it right from here okay
so I can click on pass and it is going
to set the results to past
or if I want to fail The Next Step then
I can also do that okay
now there is also an option to post the
execution uh if you have running the
automated test and you want to pause the
execution then you can this option will
be enabled and you can click on that to
post the execution
now finally once you are completed with
your manual test case execution you can
go ahead and finish your test case
execution
and now you will see a additional
execution log has been added for our
manual test execution and it will show
you all the steps which have been passed
and which have been failed during your
manual test execution
also you can see that the screenshot
which we added it is already added here
okay
along with the comment that this step
has passed this is what we added during
our manual execution so all of this you
can do uh both for your manual tests as
well as for your automated test you can
execute all your test steps manually
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video